Guide to the Dept. of Household Economics and Management Research studies, 1913-1971,
Dept.of Household Economics and Management Research studies
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Dept. of Household Economics and Management Research studies, 1913-1971, 1920-1971 (bulk)
23-18-1648
New York State College of Home Economics.Department of Household Economics and Management.
34 cubic ft., 126 volumes, 10 reels microfilm
Research Materials, microfilm
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
New York State College of Home Economics Dept. of Household Economics and Management Research studies
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Specific surveys include: management of family finances, Livingston Co., NY, 1928-29; cost of living for farm families, Tompkins Co., NY, 1928-29; economic contributions of household members, NY State, 1960-61; financial management practices of young families, Tompkins Co., NY, 1955-58; financial management in relation to family values and concepts of financial security, Norwich, NY, 1961; financial management of graduate women, Cornell University, 1955; financial management from marriage to 1935, Tompkins and Livingston Counties, NY, 1935; food shopping practices of families, Cleveland, OH and Rochester, NY, 1939; kinds and amounts of representative foods used during one week, Cleveland, OH and Rochester, NY, 1938; management of food purchases and meals, NY State, 1959; food consumption of farm and village families, central NY State, 1927; inventories of outerwear of farm families, Tompkins Co., NY, 1950; types of equipment found in homes, Buffalo, NY, 1949; repair of small household electrical appliances, Canandaigua, NY, 1956; use of small kitchen equipment by young families, Ithaca, NY and vicinity, 1936; use of carpentry tools as a home management resource, NY State, 1945; major equipment work space, and storage space in homes, Ithaca, NY and vicinity, 1936-42; acceptance of the mechanical dishwasher, Rochester, NY, 1955-56; laundry practices and equipment, Erie, PA, 1959; and family laundry practices and costs, Tompkins Co., NY, 1945.
Also, buying and selling potatoes in retail groceries, Cleveland, Ohio and Rochester, NY, 1937-38; price variation in retail grocery stores, NY State, 1935; availability and price of fruits and vegetables in retail stores, Ithaca, NY, 1942-45; store practices and the sale of washing machines on credit, NY State, 1938-40; size of purchasing centers of families, NY State, 1928; a study of credit bureaus, NY State, 1940-42; decision-making concerning household activities, NY State, 1957; daily activities of homemakers confined to wheel chairs, Ithaca, NY and vicinity, 1954; distance traveled in farm homes when preparing and serving food and washing dishes, Seneca Co., NY, 1949-51; financial education at the secondary school level, Sherburne, NY, 1949; and selection of heat for cooking, NY, 1953.
SUBJECTS
Names:
New York State College of Home Economics.; Walker, Kathryn.; Warren, Jean.; Wiegand, Elizabeth.; Cornell University--Students.
Subjects:
Households--Research.; Home economics.; Credit bureaus.; Handicapped women.; Women college students.; Time study.
Places:
New York (State)--Surveys.; Livingston County (N.Y.)--Surveys.; Tompkins County (N.Y.)--Surveys.; Seneca County (N.Y.)--Surveys.; Norwich (N.Y.)--Surveys.; Rochester (N.Y.)--Surveys.; Buffalo (N.Y.)--Surveys.; Canandaigua (N.Y.)--Surveys.; Ithaca (N.Y.)--Surveys.; Sherburne (N.Y.)--Surveys.; Cleveland (Ohio)--Surveys.; Erie (Pa.)--Surveys.
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Restricted to educational and research purposes.
Partial listing of collection only.
CONTAINER LIST
- Correspondence Concerning the Department of Household Economics and Management Class Projects, Ithaca and Tompkins County--Kitchen Remodeling, 1931; 1933; 1935 (Box 1, Folder 1-8)
- Purnell Act Research-Laundry, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Laundry Costs, 1930-1948 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Seminar-Publications Concerning Clothing, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Cowles Technical Tips-Publication, 1934-1935 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Research Methods, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Clothing Inventories of Outerwear of 103 New York Farm Families, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Laundry-Publications, 1931-1948 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Can Labels (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Consumer Purchases of Canned Tomatoes Labeled in Various Ways-Thesis, 1941-1942 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Consumer Purchases of Canned Tomatoes and Peaches as Related to Retail Store Offerings in Buffalo Supermarkets, 1941-1942 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Labeling-Publications, 1940s (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Records, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Suggestions for Further Study of Data Collected by Josephine Kramer, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Financial History of Farm Families-Tompkins and Livingston Counties, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Records-Livingston County, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Directions for Making Lists of Families to be Visited for Copying Data, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Farm Management Records-Dryden, 1907, 1917, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Family Attitudes-Tompkins and Livingston Counties, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Farm Management Records-Lansing, 1908, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Farm Management Records-Hilton, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Farm Management Records-Livingston County, 1928-1929 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Financial Management by 427 New York Farm Families from Marriage Until 1935-Josephine Kramer, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Correspondence-Credit Bureaus, 1938-1939 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Improvements Suggested for Work Centers and Storage Centers in 916 Kitchens in New York State; Kitchen Floors and Floor Coverings-Both by Mildred Spicer, 1930-1937; 1939 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Correspondence-Purchasing Centers, 1927-1929 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- President's Conference on Home Building and Home Ownership-A Study of Housing in Relation to Family Development-Surveys (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Radio Talk and Publicity, 1940s (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Frozen Food Research, 1942-1948 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Frozen Food Research, 1943-1949 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Correspondence Concerning Freezing Units, 1942-1944 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Articles on Food Pricing, 1947-1954 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Data on Food Pricing, 1938-1942 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- President's Conference on Home Building and Home Ownership, 1931-1932 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- President's Conference on Home Building and Home Ownership, 1930-1931 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- President's Conference on Home Building and Home Ownership-Committee on Technical Developments; Committee on Education and Service, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- President's Conference on Home Building and Home Ownership-Committee on Large-Scale Operations, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- President's Conference on Home Building and Home Ownership-Various Committee Reports and Directory of Committee Personnel, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- President's Conference on Home Building and Home Ownership-Suggestions and Recommendations for Local Action, 1932 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Synopsis of Studies Made for the Committee on Housing and Family Development, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Economic Study of Food Consumed by Farm and Village Families in Central New York, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Cost if Living Study-Sample Questionnaires, 1929-1951 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Index Numbers of the Cost of Goods and Services Bought by Farm Families in New York; Methods of Construction, 1920-1935 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Cost of Buying Food-Teaching Materials, 19341-1938 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Material Used at Washington Meeting Concerning USDA Index, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Farm and Home Week-Staff Lectures, 1937-1960 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- The School of Living-Suffern, New York, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- U.S. President's 7-Point Program to Control the Cost of Living-County Conferences to Consider Program, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Business Facts for Homemakers-Cooperative Extension Project, 1949-1958 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Kitchen Floors and Stoves-Cooperative Extension Project, 1931-1933 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Family Financial Management-Summary; Teaching Materials, 1919-1932; 1929-1957 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Money Management-Publications from Various States, 1934-1951 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Dishwashing and Cooking Utensils-Cooperative Extension Project, 1928-1946 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Kitchen Arrangement-Bulletins, Slide Scripts, 1947-1956 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Kitchen Improvement-Reports, Bulletins, Projects, 1931-1946 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Kitchen Design-Illustrations (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Soapmaking-Cushman's Teaching Material, 1929-1934 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Development and Home Management-Correpondence and Reports, 1946-1949 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Homemakers' Use of Time, 1930 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Modern Methods of Housecleaning-Cooperative Extension Project, 1931-1934 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Management Tours to Home-Teaching Methods Developed by Prof. Cushman, 1944-1953 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Kitchen Tours-Teaching Method, 1936-1957 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Overcoming Fatigue-Cooperative Extension Project Developed by Prof. Cushman, 1934-1941 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Overcoming Fatigue, 1942-1944 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Home Mangement Projects in Cooperative Extension, 1921-1937 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Course Material-Prof. Cushman, 1933-1953 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Course Material-Prof. Cushman, 1938-1949 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Development of a Successful Kitchen-Class Report, 1935 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Photos of Prof. Cushman's Home on Hanshaw Road, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Development of Organization of a Home Sewing Center-Prof. Cushman, 1927-1929 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Publications Prepared by Other States Concerning Equipment, 1931-1947 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Cornell Publications Concerning Equipment, 1936-1952 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- President's Conference on Home Building and Home Ownership-Committee on Types of Dwellings, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- President's Conference on Home Building and Home Ownership-Committee on Kitchens and Other Work Centers, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- President's Conference on Home Building and Home Ownership-Committee on Subdivision Layout, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- President's Conference on Home Building and Home Ownership-Committee on Industrial Decentralization and Housing, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- President's Conference on Home Building and Home Ownership-Committee on Blighted Areas and Slums, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- President's Conference on Home Building and Home Ownership-Committee on Construction, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- President's Conference on Home Building and Home Ownership-Committee on Design, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- President's Conference on Home Building and Home Ownership-Committee on City Planning and Zoning, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- President's Conference on Home Building and Home Ownership-Committee on Finance, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- President's Conference on Home Building and Home Ownership-Committee on Taxation, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- President's Conference on Home Building and Home Ownership-Committee on Home Ownership and Leasing, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- President's Conference on Home Building and Home Ownership-Committee on Home Furnishing and Decoration, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- President's Conference on Home Building and Home Ownership-Committee on Lanscape Planning and Planting, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 30)
- President's Conference on Home Building and Home Ownership-Various Committee Reports, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 31)
- President's Conference on Home Building and Home Ownership-Committee on Household Management-Relative Values in Household Management, 1931 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- President's Conference on Home Building and Home Ownership-Committee on Household Management-Purchasing Procedures, 1931 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- President's Conference on Home Building and Home Ownership-Committee on Household Management-Scheduling Household Tasks; Storage Spaces, 1931 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- President's Conference on Home Building and Home Ownership-Committee on Household Management-Home Information Services and Centers, 1931 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- President's Conference on Home Building and Home Ownership-Committee on Household Management-Committee on the Relationship of Income and the Home-Buffalo Home Ownership Study, 1931 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- President's Conference on Home Building and Home Ownership-Committee on Household Management-Committee on Farm and Village Housing-Bibliographies, 1931 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- President's Conference on Home Building and Home Ownership-Committee on Household Management-Committee on Farm and Village Housing-Education and Guidance, 1931 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- President's Conference on Home Building and Home Ownership-Committee on Farm and Village Housing-Design and Construction, 1931 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- President's Conference on Home Building and Home Ownership-Committee on Farm and Village Housing-Economic Factors in Farm and Village Home Ownership and Improvement, 1931 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- President's Conference on Home Building and Home Ownership-Committee on Farm and Village Housing-Sanitation, Farmstead Planning and Beautification, 1931 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- President's Conference on Home Building and Home Ownership-Committee on Farm and Village Housing-Housing of Special Groups, 1931 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- President's Conference on Home Building and Home Ownership-Committee on Farm and Village Housing-Special Reports, 1931 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- President's Conference on Home Building and Home Ownership-Committee on Housing and the Community, 1931 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- President's Conference on Home Building and Home Ownership-Committee on Negro Housing, 1931 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- President's Conference on Home Building and Home Ownership-Committee on Home Information Services and Centers, 1931 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- President's Conference on Home Building and Home Ownership-Committee on Home information Services and Centers, 1931 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- President's Conference on Home Building and Home Ownership-Committee on Home information Services and Centers, 1931 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Housing Reports from Kansas State College, 1931 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Housing Reports-Resource Material Used for the Committe on Homemaking, Housing and Family Life, 1931 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Housing and Family Life Committee Reports, 1931 (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Robert Foster's Study on Home Conditions on Family Life, 1932 (Box 4, Folder 21)
- List of Heads of Home Economics Departments in the U.S., 1931 (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Correspondence-Claribel Nye, Lawrence Frank (Box 4, Folder 23)
- President's Conference on Home Building and Ownership-Memoranda, 1931 (Box 4, Folder 24)
- O.C. Carmichael's Reports on Housing, 1931 (Box 4, Folder 25)
- City Housing Report (Box 4, Folder 26)
- Circular Letters (Box 4, Folder 27)
- Publications Committee (Box 4, Folder 28)
- Committees Housing (Box 4, Folder 29)
- Outlines Housing (Box 4, Folder 30)
- Plans, Photos, Descriptions, and Write-ups of Home Economics Projects in the Kitchens and Storage Areas of Local Residents (Alphabetical Listing A-D), 1938-1971 (Box 5, Folder 1-69)
- Plans, Photos, Descriptions, and Write-ups of Home Economics Projects in the Kitchens and Storage Areas of Local Residents (Alphabetical Listing E-J), 1938-1971 (Box 6, Folder 1-53)
- Plans, Photos, Descriptions, and Write-ups of Home Economics Projects in the Kitchens and Storage Areas of Local Residents (Alphabetical Listing K-M), 1943-1971 (Box 7, Folder 1-57)
- Plans, Photos, Descriptions, and Write-ups of Home Economics Projects in the Kitchens and Storage Areas of Local Residents (Alphabetical Listing N-S), 1940-1971 (Box 8, Folder 1-68)
- Plans, Photos, Descriptions, and Write-ups of Home Economics Projects in the Kitchens and Storage Areas of Local Residents (Alphabetical Listing S-W), 1939-1968 (Box 9, Folder 1-45)
- Photos, Misc. Class Projects, Household Activities Manual (Box 10, Folder 1-25)
- Farm Homemakers' Use of Time, Genesee County, 1936
- Batavia No. 11-114 (Box 11, Volume 1)
- Batavia No. 115-187 (Box 11, Volume 2)
- Batavia No. 190-303 (Box 11, Volume 3)
- Bergen No. 3-76 (Box 11, Volume 4)
- Bergen No. 78-171 (Box 12, Volume 5)
- Bethany No. 4-90 (Box 12, Volume 6)
- Bethany No. 95-175 (Box 12, Volume 7)
- Bryon (Box 12, Volume 8)
- Pavilion No. 2-93 (Box 12, Volume 9)
- Pavilion No. 94-181 (Box 13, Volume 10)
- Stafford No. 1-108 (Box 13, Volume 11)
- Stafford No. 111-196 (Box 13, Volume 12)
- Seasonal Records from All Townships (Box 13, Volume 13)
- Consumer Preference for Potatoes, 1936-1939
- Retail Store Supply
- Cleveland, OH, 1936-1938 (Box 14, Volume 1)
- Rochester, NY, 1937-1938 (Box 14, Volume 2)
- Consumer Store Record
- Cleveland, OH, 1936 (Box 14, Volume 3-5)
- Cleveland, OH, 1937 (Box 15, Volume 6-7)
- Cleveland, OH, 1938 (Box 15, Volume 8-9)
- Rochester, NY, 1937 (Box 15, Volume 10)
- Rochester, NY, 1938 (Box 16, Volume 11)
- Rochester, NY, 1939 (Box 16, Volume 12)
- Consumer Home Record
- Cleveland, OH, 1936 (Box 16, Volume 13-21)
- Cleveland, OH, 1937 (Box 18, Volume 22-25)
- Cleveland, OH, 1938 (Box 19, Volume 26-30)
- Rochester, NY, 1937 (Box 20, Volume 31-35)
- Rochester, NY, 1938 (Box 21, Volume 36-38)
- Rochester, NY, 1938 (Box 21, Volume 39-41)
- Household Management by Farm Families, 1927-1928
- Dryden No. 108-522 (Box 22, Volume 1-6)
- Lansing No. 4-478 (Box 23, Volume 7-9)
- Practices in Installment Selling in New York State, 1938
- No. 10323, 1938 (Box 23, Volume 1-3)
- Use of Time of Farm and City Full-Time Homemakers and Homemakers in the Labor Force, 1952
- Geneseo County
- No. 1-50 (Box 24, Volume 1)
- No. 51-101 (Box 24, Volume 2)
- Auburn, NY
- No. 1-50 (Box 24, Volume 3)
- No. 51-100 (Box 24, Volume 4)
- No. 102-157 (Box 24, Volume 5)
- Some Practices in the Management of Food Purchases on Meals, 1958
- No. 1-2 (Box 25, Volume 1)
- No. 3-4 (Box 25, Volume 2)
- No. 5-6 (Box 25, Volume 3)
- No. 7-8 (Box 25, Volume 4)
- Merchants Practices in Credit Investigation, New York State, 1940
- No. 1-295 (Box 25, Volume 1-2)
- Practices of Credit Bureaus, 1940
- (Box 25, Volume 1)
- Families' Decisions in the Care of Laundry, 1945
- No. 1-186 (Box 26, Volume 1-2)
- No. 200-324 (Box 26, Volume 3)
- No. 400-524 (Box 26, Volume 4)
- The Workload and its Values for 50 Homeowners, 1958
- Tompkins County, NY, No. 1-50 (Box 26, Volume 1)
- Major Equipment and Conveniences Used in Household Tasks, 1939
- Dryden School District (Box 27, Volume 1)
- Homer School District (Box 27, Volume 2)
- Newark School District, No. 101-135 (Box 27, Volume 3)
- Newark School District, No. 136-174 (Box 27, Volume 4)
- Basic Distances in 100 Farm Homes for Preparing Food, 1949
- Upper Economic Group, No. 1-70 (Box 27, Volume 1)
- Lower Economic Group, No. 1-84 (Box 27, Volume 2)
- Financial Management Practices of Young Families, by Wells, 1957
- No. 1-33 (Box 28, Volume 1)
- No. 34-65 (Box 28, Volume 2)
- No. 69-535 (Box 28, Volume 3)
- Family Decisions about the Conduct of Household Tasks as Related to Human and Material Resources of the Home, by Davis, 1956
- No. 4-24 (Box 28, Volume 1)
- No. 26-46 (Box 28, Volume 2)
- No. 47-63 (Box 28, Volume 3)
- No. 64-77 (Box 28, Volume 4)
- Records for Study of Economic Contributions and Receipts of Household Members, 1953
- No. 1-30 (Box 29, Volume 1)
- No. 31-60 (Box 29, Volume 2)
- No. 61-90 (Box 29, Volume 3)
- No. 91-120 (Box 29, Volume 4)
- No. 121-150 (Box 29, Volume 5)
- No. 151-225 (Box 29, Volume 6)
- No. 226-255 (Box 29, Volume 7)
- Clothing Inventories of Outerwear of New York Farm Families, 1950
- No. 1-72 (Box 30, Volume 1)
- No. 204-247 (Box 30, Volume 2)
- No. 259-247 (Box 30, Volume 3)
- No. 402-480 (Box 30, Volume 4)
- No. 600-915 (Box 30, Volume 5)
- No. 151-225 (Box 30, Volume 6)
- No. 226-255 (Box 30, Volume 7)
- Management in Relation to the Care of its House--Living Room Cleaning Practices and Attitudes of Homemakers and Their Relationships to Family Use of the Living Room, 1954
- No. 2-76 (Box 30, Volume 1)
- No. 80-175 (Box 31, Volume 2)
- No. 176-259 (Box 31, Volume 3)
- No. 261-361 (Box 31, Volume 4)
- No. 364-483 (Box 31, Volume 5)
- No. 485-586 (Box 31, Volume 6)
- No. 627-680 (Box 31, Volume 7)
- No. 685-850 (Box 31, Volume 8)
- Economic Contributions Made by Families to Their Newly Married Children, 1960
- No. 1-28 (Box 32, Volume 1)
- No. 29-54 (Box 32, Volume 2)
- No. 101-128 (Box 32, Volume 3)
- No. 129-153 (Box 32, Volume 4)
- Financial Management in Relation to Family Values and Concepts of Financial Security, 1960
- No. 1-32 (Box 32, Volume 1)
- No. 101-133 (Box 32, Volume 2)
- History of Financial Management of Farm Families (Vols. 8-9 at K-230-A-1), 1935
- Livingston County
- Avon (Box 33, Volume 1)
- Geneseo (Box 33, Volume 2)
- Lima (Box 33, Volume 3)
- York (Box 33, Volume 4)
- Caledonia (Box 33, Volume 5)
- Tompkins County
- Dryden (Box 33, Volume 6)
- Lansing (Box 33, Volume 7)
- Membership Study, 1958
- (Box 34, Volume 1-7)
- History of the New York State College of Agriculture at Cornell University, by Colman, 1963
- (Box 34, Volume 1)